

JOHN LOUISE L. BERDIDA

212-E C.Padilla Cebu City, Philippines - Cebu 6000

Cell: 09239414642

Email: jLkisni21@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An experienced Software Engineer in Information Technology mostly in Insurance, Banking and System Application and Products as a developer under the AS/400/ISeries environment, Java Development and Php MVC Frameworks such as Laravel/CodeIgniter. Full project life cycle development experience with major strengths in project implementation methodologies and quality assurance best practices. Supportive and enthusiastic team player dedicated to streamlined processes and efficiently resolving project issues. Willing to take ownership of core components.

SKILLS

- Cobol/400, AS400 specialist
- Advance knowledge of PHP
- E-commerce background
- Data management
- Troubleshooting and debugging
- Strong decision maker
- Performance and scalability optimization

- Java Programming specialist
- PHP MVC Specialist
- API design knowledge
- MySQL
- Data Warehousing and Analytics
- Javascript

WORK HISTORY

11/2017 to Current

Software Engineer (Offshore Development)

Total eBiz Solutions Pte Ltd (Prudential Assurance Corp.) - Singapore

- Rapidly prototyped new capabilities to confirm feasibility
- Directed software design and development while remaining focused on client needs.
- Unit Statements(Life/400 MAS 307 Compliance)
- Reserve Pricing (Life/400)
- Spooling Reports (Life/400)

09/2017 to 11/2017

Software Engineer (Offshore Development)

Total eBiz Solutions Pte Ltd (Maybank Singapore) - Singapore

- Researched, designed and implemented scalable application for information identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval and indexing.
- Involved in maintenance, support and enhancements for Credit Card Application call Semacard.
- Change control to house customization and development.
- Worked effectively with design teams to ensure software solutions elevated client side experience.

05/2017 to 08/2017

Software Engineer (Offshore Development)

Total eBiz Solutions Pte Ltd (Tokio Marine Insurance) - Singapore

- Researched, designed and implemented scalable applications for information identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval and indexing.
- Directed software design and development while remaining focus on client needs.
- Rapidly prototyped new capabilities to confirm feasibility.
- Stored, retrieved and manipulated data for close analysis of system capabilities.
- Worked closely with other team members to plan, design and develop robust solutions in a timely manner.
- Wrote maintainable and extensible code in a team environment.
- Implemented designs, including experimentation and multiple iterations.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, upgrade interfaces and improve performance.

11/2016 to 05/2017

Software Engineer (Offshore Development)

Total eBiz Solutions Pte Ltd (China Life Insurance Com.) - Singapore

- Analyzed department documents for appropriate distribution and filing.
- Assisted various business group with document organization and dissemination during acquisitions.
- Research, design, and implement scalable applications for information identification, extraction, analyst, retrieval, and indexing.
- Direct software design and development while remaining focused on client needs.
- Interface with business analysts, developers, and technical support to determine optimal specifications.
- Collaborate closely with other team members to plan, design, and develop robust solution.

• Convert the user requirement into Business, Functional and technical Specifications.

07/2015 to 08/2016

Java Instructor

Call Center Academy - Cebu City, Central Visayas

- Clearly communicated objectives for all lessons, units and projects to all participants regarding to java programming.
- Strengthened their development methodologies by introducing a code quality document.
- Introducing implemented innovative systems for data collection and storage.

01/2015 to 04/2015

Lead Web Developer

Call Center Academy - Cebu City, central Visayas

- Lead the team and distribute the task to the developers for Maria Cristina Arcade Web Application that involves:
- Prototyping and research development
- Wrote and implemented scripts to enhance user experience and integrated scripts with the CMS.
- Implemented innovative systems for data collection, storage and management of customer orders.
- Debugged and modified software components.
- Designed PHP Programing-based multi-threaded admin web applications.

04/2014 to 11/2016

Freelance Web Developer

Online Freelancing Service - Cebu City, Philippines - Cebu

- Devised tracking software with modules for inventory monitoring customer relationship management, staff administration and the generation reports.
- Maintained existing applications and designed and delivered new application.
- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.

EDUCATION

2016

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

University of Cebu - Main Campus - Cebu City, Central Visayas, Philippines